<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="1_test_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>

<letter>
<head>
<location state = "VA">Darby town Road Richmond va</location>
<date day = "1" month = "December" year = "1864" standard = "18641201">Dec 1st 1864</date>

<sal>Dear <pers role = "recip">Mother</pers></sal>
</head>
<body>
    Your letters by <pers role = "ref" job = "lieutenant" allegiance = "c">Lt Wilhelm</pers> <!--[i.e., Lt. William M. Wilhelm, Co. K, 8th North Carolina Infantry]--> &amp; <pers role = "ref" job = "private" allegiance = "c">Ben Cauble</pers> <!--[i.e., Pvt. Benjamin Cauble, Co. B, 42nd North Carolina Infantry]--> came to hand last night. <emotion mood = "happy">I was glad to hear from home.</emotion> I recd the comfort &amp; gloves I send the comfort back for I think they do more harm than good You need not send my over coat for I have enough to carry now there is a pistol in our Co for sale if I can get it for less than one ($100) hundred Dollars I will send it by the Lieut.
<emotion mood = "afraid">Ma I witnessed something the other day that I never saw before &amp; never wish to see again one of our Brigade was shot for desertion poor fellow I could not help pitying him when he was marched around the Brigade we were formed in a hollow square he was placed upon his coffin and a white cloth placed over his eyes and then the command was given Ready. Aaim. Fire. and twelve rifles were discharged only six were loaded five balls struck him and the Dr dismounted at the discharge and examined his pulse and came back and reported <!--(to Col McKethan comdg Brig) [i.e., Col. Hector M. McKethan, 51st North Carolina Infantry] -->him dead &amp; we were marched back to our quarters. oh it was awful.</emotion> <pers role = "ref" job = "captain" allegiance = "c">Capt Cook</pers> <!--[i.e., Capt. Jonas Cook, Co. H, 8th North Carolina Infantry]--> has arrived he says tell <pers role = "ref">Pa</pers> <!--[i.e., William M. Barker]--> he must excuse him for not calling on him he met up with <pers role = "ref" job = "lieutenant" allegiance="c">Lt Wilhelm</pers> &amp; did not have a chance to do so. <emotion mood = "happy">I think I would have laughed if I had been home at the time the prisoners broke loose ask Pa if his gun was loaded &amp; how many rounds of blank cartidges he had and if he had bayonets fixed or if he was scared much.</emotion>
<pers role = "ref" job = "private" allegiance = "c">Abraham Morgan</pers> <!--[i.e., Pvt. Abram Morgan, Co. K, 8th North Carolina Infantry]--> is home on (30) thirty days furlough you can send me a box by him when he returns. If you can get those cloths I wrote about you will have an oportunity to send them. Tell <pers role = "ref">Mrs Allen</pers> <!--[i.e., Amanda A. Allen]--> if we are ordered to go we will do so but we dont want to be ordered again give my respects to all of our family &amp; <pers role = "ref">Mrs Shumans</pers> <!--[i.e., Elvira L. Shuman's] -->. &amp; <pers role = "ref">Mrs Allen</pers> and write soon &amp; send me some writing paper &amp; envelops by <pers role = "ref" job = "private" allegiance="c">Morgan</pers>
</body>
<close>
<val>
my love to all
write Soon to

Your Affectionate Son
</val>
<pers role = "sender" job = "soldier" allegiance = "c">Cicero R Barker</pers>

<ps>P.S. Tell <pers role = "ref">Willie</pers> <!--[i.e., William R. Barker, the author's brother] --> I am much obliged to him for the gloves

<pers role = "sender" job = "soldier" allegiance = "c">Cicero R Barker</pers>

[illeg] &amp; <pers role = "ref">Harry</pers> are well</ps>
</close>
</letter>