<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="1_test_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>

<letter>
<head>
<location state = "VA">2nd Div. Hospital 9th
Corps Near Petersburg.Va.</location><date day ="22" month = "August" year = "1864" standard = "18640822">Aug.22nd 1864</date>
<sal>Dear <pers role = "recip">Mother</pers>.</sal>
</head>
    
<body>
<emotion mood = "sad">Yes. I am at last in the hospital. I hated to tell you for you will think I am quite sick which is not the case. I have got sort of tired out.</emotion> <emotion mood = "hopeful">All I need is a chance to rest and I will be all right in a few days. I am not so sick as most of our boys have to be to get to the rear.</emotion> Our Regt. has moved since I wrote you but I have not been quite up with the Regt. since they got down here. I should think I was some three miles from where I was when I wrote before, to the left. <emotion mood = "digusted">Yesterday I was out here by the amputating table when many of the wounded were brought in. And I saw them cut off any number of hands and feet. Poor fellows. Several of them died right away after having been operated upon.</emotion> <emotion mood = "triumphant">For awhile yesterday the cannonading was truly terrific. I miss the sound of musketry. I can hear the cannons here if they have an engagement.</emotion> <emotion mood = "bittersweet">The quiet seems rather good on the whole. still it seems a little lonesome.</emotion> <emotion mood = "triumphant"><unit>The 5th Corps</unit> did some good fighting and took a pretty good lot of prisoners, mostly S. Carolinians and stout hard looking fellows</emotion>. <emotion mood = "sad">Pretty much the whole of the <unit>16th ME.</unit> were captured <pers role = "ref" job = "colonel" allegiance = "u">Col. Tilden</pers> <!--[i.e., Lt. Col. Charles W. Tilden, 16th Maine Infantry]--> among the rest. I dont know any in particular that were taken.</emotion> I saw <pers role = "ref">Mr. Balkan</pers> their Chaplain yesterday. As regards the war news you get that by the papers long before a letter gets there. <emotion mood = "defiant">I will just say that we have the Weldon railroad and if old <pers role = "ref">Lee</pers> gets it back he has something of a job before him.</emotion> <unit>The 5th Corps</unit> were fortifying very strongly on the railroad and a part of the <unit>2nd Corps</unit> came down as a support yesterday, and I was told that Butler's corps was back of us but I think that a mistake. I came here today but before I came I got six letters. One from you and <pers role = "ref">Delinda</pers> <!--[i.e., Delinda Jackson]--> and one from <pers role = "ref" job = "sergeant" allegiance="u">Sergt. Arnold</pers> <!--[i.e., Sgt. Lloyd Q. Arnold, Co. D, 32nd Maine Infantry]-->. those were all I cared for at all. the others were business letters and business has but few charms for me as I feel now. I feel all the interest in the business at home that I ever did but this business here is not of a kind to make one love it. <emotion mood = "happy">I was very pleased as usual to hear from you -- to get a letter written by your own hand. I dont know what I should do if I did not hear from home oftener than a great part of our boys do.</emotion> <emotion mood = "bittersweet">I am here to fight for those at home that I love and if they did not prize my services, and life it may, sufficiently to write to cheer me I fear I should sink. I agree with you that it is mostly unpleasant here but there are some pleasant things even here sometimes.</emotion> <emotion mood = "afraid">There never was such a campaign before since the creation of the world as we have been passing through this season. I trust it is the last such one the world will ever know like it.</emotion> <emotion mood = "hopeful">I hope to be spared to return to you and I feel as if I should but this world is not intended as a state of perfect bliss. Thank God. He has prepared a world of perfect bliss and I trust we will both enjoy it. We will if I am not deceived in my hope. I love to look forward to our meeting on earth. I shall be so glad to see you and clasp you in my arms once more. Every thing about there seems pleasant by contrast to think of even those that I used to dislike. I wish they would rush the men down here and I believe this thing might be settled up pretty soon.</emotion> <emotion mood = "bittersweet">I expect to be able to go back to the Regt. in a few days but I dont intend to hurry. I dont feel that our Regt has been used right. that makes a difference with me.</emotion>
</body>
<close>
<val>Your affectionate son</val>
<pers role = "sender" job = "sergeant" allegiance = "u">John [Mower Jackson]</pers>

<ps>Please write often. remember how well soldiers love to hear from their mothers.</ps>
</close>
</letter>