<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="1_test_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<letter>
    <head>
        <location state = "OH">"Island Home,"</location>
        <date day="5" month="February" year="1865" standard="18650205">Feb 5" 1865</date>
    
        <sal>My dear cousin <pers role="recip" allegiance="c">Mattie</pers>:</sal>
    </head>
    
    <body>Yours of the <date day="18" month="January" year="1865" standard="18650118">18" ulto.</date> reached me yesterday. <emotion mood="bittersweet">Its kind and cheerful tone at once drove away all gloomy thoughts and dispelled the dark clouds that had been hovering over me for the past few days.</emotion> <emotion mood="hopeful">would that I could get such letters every day. it would render even prison life endurable</emotion> -- <emotion mood="happy">I am greatly rejoiced to learn that my pleasur letters aford you pleasure</emotion> -- <emotion mood="afraid">I much feared that they would prove too great a tax upon your "patience"</emotion> I write you every week, generaly on Sunday -- "<pers role="ref">Job</pers> was indeed a patient man, but you must recolect that he lived in times of Peace, and I do not believe he had any relations at all. I wrote you imediately upon the recept of the box returning thanks &amp; c -- which I hope has reached you ere this. I can see that cake now, with "Mattie" impressed in large gilt letters upon its sufrice -- It will not be forgotten soon -- <emotion mood="hopeful">You did right to trust in "<pers role="ref" job="deity">providence</pers>," He will always reward those who put their trust in Him. Many thanks dear <pers role="recip" allegiance="c">Mattie</pers> for the $$ </emotion>-- <emotion mood="hopeless">I much confess that I was really in need of a small supply of funds at the time, My washers &amp; cooks bills coming in at once quite exhausted my stock, leaving my Pipe cold and my supply of stationary completely exhausted.</emotion> But you must recolect these little things I shall claim the right hereafter of returning the favor. <emotion mood="bittersweet">I do not meet with such friends often and shall take good care that these acts of kindness shown me in this, my hour of need meet with proper reward</emotion> -- "It is bread cast upon the waters" -- <emotion mood="sad">I am under special obligation dear cousin for writing to my Uncle -- I have written to him time and again since I have been a prisoner but met with no success</emotion> -- I wrote by way of <place state="KY">Paducah</place> &amp; <place state="KY">Mayfield</place> to the care of merchants living at these places -- which party claim <place state="TN">that portion of Tennessee lying between the Tennessee and Missippi rivers? containing the counties of Henry &amp; Weakley</place>? -- <emotion mood="hopeful">I have just received a letter from my brother in <place state="NC">Raleigh n.c.</place> saying he had shipped me a box of provisions in <date month="October" year="1864" standard="18641000">Oct. last</date>. I am in luck.</emotion> <pers role="recip" allegiance="c">Cousin Mattie</pers> will you send me your Photo.? Do please -- You know I have not seen you since you were a little girl -- forgive me for writing so small -- I had just so many lines &amp; I wished to put in all my [illeg] -- did you get the "ballad"</body>
    
    <close><val>Your Affectionate Cous,</val>
    <pers role="sender" allegiance="c" job="soldier">James B. Jordan</pers>,
    
    <pers role="recip" allegiance="c">Miss Mattie Fearn</pers>
    <location state="KY">"Hunters Bottom"
    Milton, Ky,</location></close>
</letter>
