<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="test_schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<letter>
<head>
<location state="MS">Hd Qts Signal Corps</location>
<date day="3" month="May" year="1864" standard="18640503">May 3rd 1864</date>

<pers role = "recip">My dear Sister</pers>
</head>
<body>
To day is a leasure day with me and I will write you a few lines, which I have been intending to do for a long while, but have put off from time to time thinking every day I would write, but I find the old adage a true one, "Never put off for tomorrow that which can be done to day;" Though I knew that you heard from me through Parkie or Norton one, but that is not like writing some times myself.
<emotion mood="happy">I have been stationed in <place state = "VA">King George Co.</place> every since the Middle of January last, I had a delightful time I formd a great many acquaintances &amp; they were all very kind to me, made me a great many presents such as socks, &amp; C, they were constantly sending me somthing good to Eat, which I stood in need of at times, for it was so very inconvenient for me to get my rations.</emotion> I was a regular church attendant, I was stationed not far from St; Paul's church where there was preaching every Sabbath.<emotion mood="sad">I was very sorry when I had to leave, I received orders a few days ago to report here, Dick had received orders from <pers role = "ref" job="general" allegiance="c">Gen; Stuart</pers> to send him a portion of his Corps to Orange CH.o. and he wanted me as one of them to send, but Ben. &amp; myself persuaded him to allow us to remain with him, for I expect very soon to have traveling enough to do.</emotion> 
How are you getting on house keeping &amp; how do you like Richmond, from all I can learn times must be very hard on you all, Every thing is so very high, but if you can make out to live you are better off than if you were in the country, Espicially if you were in old New Kent.<emotion mood="digusted"> There you would not only have hard times to contend with, but you would have those vile retches to contend with, (the yankees) which is worse than all I think.</emotion> I expect in a very short time the hold county will be filled with them, I see from to days papers that they are reported landing at west point, I feel very sorry for the citizens that are left down in that country, they are bound to suffer &amp; that badly, for they are doing much worse now than they have ever done before, every where, I feel very much for cousin Susan &amp; family I cant imagine what they will do, if they should bring up a large force.
<emotion mood="happy">I hear from Mary [i.e., Mary E. Savage, the author's sister] quite often, I am glad to hear she is so much pleased with her new situation &amp; the family whom she is with. She say's they are very kind to her.</emotion> I also hear that Parkie [i.e., Maria Parker Savage, the author's sister] has gotten a situation in the Dpt. in which Mary left, there was a rumour in circulation a few days ago that all the Clerks would be ordered to Columbia S. C. but I understand that the order has been countermanded, tho; I hardly expect Parkie would have been willing to have gone, she wrote me word that their pay had been increased, I am very glad to hear it. I did not think myself they were paying them enough, taking in consideration our Confederate money was of such little valure.
How, and where is Nat [i.e., Nathaniel L. Savage (b. 1854), the author's son], I suppose he is going to school some where. Well; I must close my letter, tho I feel as if I could sit &amp;; talk to you a hold day without stoping. I want to see you all so much, I have no war news to write you, tho; I expect you hear a plenty of that in Richd I am very well indeed, enjoying fine health. We are getting a plenty of fine fish, do wish so much you had some of them, write to me, in one of your leasure hours. Good bye
your affectionate Brother, Southy.  
Give my love all with you &amp; at Sister H's when you see them I am sorry to hear sister H's health is so bad. Also my love to them all at Brother Nortons, I would like to trade you some fish for some of your nice bread.
</body>
    <close>
    <val>your Affectionate Brother</val>
<pers role = "sender" job = "soldier" allegiance="c">Southy</pers>
</close>
</letter>